Iceberg ahead!
前方 发现冰山
Hard a port!
左满舵
Captain!
船长
Are you okay?
你没事吧
Sorry for the intrusion.
打扰了
Captain...
船长
Please hold on!
请振作一点
First...officer.
副…船长
It's beautiful.
真美啊
Such a beautiful sunset.
这么美的夕阳
I wish Shinichi could see this view.
真想让新一也看看
I'm seeing it.
正在看哦
What...What's wrong?
怎…怎么了
You'll be able to see it better from up here.
从上面看可以更清楚哦
It's true that I can see better now,
虽…虽然的确能看得很清楚
but it's so embarrassing.
不过真没面子
We saw that, Conan!
看到啦 柯南
Crap.
糟糕
Let me down, Miss Ran!
放我下来 小兰姐姐
We saw that! We saw that!
看见了看见了
We saw that!
我们看见了哦
You were acting cute in front of Miss Ran again, weren't you?
你又向小兰姐撒娇了吧
Idiot!
笨蛋
It's not like that.
才不是那样
You're blushing, Conan.
你脸红了哦 柯南
What are you talking about?
说什么啊
It's because of the sunset!
是因为夕阳啦
Really? He's blushing!
真的呢 这家伙脸红了
Idiot, I'm not!
笨蛋 都说了不是啦
What are you talking about?
你说什么呀
I said it's because of the sunset.
说了是因为夕阳的关系啦
It's the same as that time.
和那个时候一样
What's the same?
什么一样
Nothing.
没什么
What is it? Tell me!
什么嘛 告诉我啦
I told you it's nothing.
什么也没有啦
How can I believe there's nothing?
怎么可能什么也没有呢
I am a high school detective, Shinichi Kudo.
我是高中生侦探工藤新一
When I went to the amusement park with my childhood friend, Ran Mouri,
有一次我和青梅竹马的同班同学毛利兰去游乐园玩的时候
I witnessed a man in black carrying out a suspicious transaction.
正巧目击到黑衣男子在进行可疑的交易
As I was too focused on the transaction,
当时我只顾着偷看交易
I failed to notice his accomplice approaching from behind.
竟没有注意到另一人正从身后靠近
He made me take the poison.
我被那人灌下了毒药
When I woke up,
醒来后发现
my body had become smaller.
身体居然变小了
If those guys knew that Shinichi Kudo was still alive,
如果让那些家伙知道工藤新一还活着的话
not only would my life be in danger,
他们一定会来追杀
I would also endanger my family and friends around me.
甚至会连累我身边的人
At the suggestion of Professor Agasa, I decided to conceal my true identity.
我听从阿笠博士的劝告决定隐姓埋名
When Ran asked for my name,
当被小兰问及名字的时候
without time to think it over, I took the name of Conan Edogawa.
情急之下 化名为江户川柯南
In order to collect information about those guys,
为了收集有关那些家伙的情报
I moved in with Ran whose father is a detective.
就借住在了父亲是侦探的小兰家里
I'm from Teitan Primary School Grade 1, Class B, Genta Kojima!
我是帝丹小学1年级B班 小岛元太
I'm his classmate, Mitsuhiko Tsuburaya!
同班的 圆谷光彦
Ayumi Yoshida!
吉田步美
And our apprentice, Conan!
手下的柯南
Along with Ai...
再加上小哀
We're the Detective Boys!
就是我们少年侦探团
This sparkling detective boys badge on my chest contains a microscopic transceiver.
在胸前闪闪发亮的是内置了超小型对讲机的侦探徽章
It has a communication function. It's absolutely wonderful!
带有发信器功能 是超棒的东西哦
This thing that's emitting light is a wristwatch flashlight.
在手腕上发光的是手表型电筒
It's waterproof, so you can even use it in the sea!
进行过防水处理 在海里也能使用哦
Both of them are Professor Agasa's inventions.
这两件都是阿笠博士的发明
In order to help the shrunken me,
博士为了帮助变小了的我
the professor invented these unique gadgets one after another.
制造出一件又一件独特的道具
Especially this Voice-Changing Bowtie,
特别是这个蝴蝶结型变声器
and this Stun-Gun Wrist-watch.
和手表型麻醉枪
Thanks to these two gadgets,
在这两样道具的说明下
the famous detective "Sleeping Kogoro" was born.
名侦探沉睡的小五郎就此诞生了
Don't you think Haibara...
话说回来 灰原她
is a little bit cool? Or rather... mature for her age.
可以说是酷吧 很有成熟的魅力啊
Of course she is.
呵呵 那当然了
Ai Haibara.
灰原哀
Her real name is Shiho Miyano.
本名宫野志保
She used to work with those men in black.
她本来是黑衣男子的同伙
In order to escape from the organization,
为了逃离组织
she took the same drug as me.
吃下了和我当时被灌下的同一种毒药
After that, her body also shrank.
身体也缩小了
That's how...
就这样
I changed from a high school detective to an elementary school detective.
我由高中生侦探变成了小学生侦探
I have solved difficult cases one after another,
在一次次解决疑难事件的过程中
In the meantime, I have been secretly trying to find out who those men in black really are.
秘密的追查着黑衣组织的真实面目
But, Mr. Mouri...
但是 毛利叔叔
Could you please work a little harder on your deductions?
能不能在推理方面再努力一点啊
Although my body is smaller, my mind is still sharp.
身体虽然变小 头脑依旧灵活
I am the famous detective that solves all the mysteries.
无所不知的名侦探
Only one truth will prevail!
真相永远只有一个
It's so spacious!
好宽敞啊
It's so luxurious!
真豪华啊
Of course it is.
这是当然的
Speaking of Yashiro Group,
说起八代集团
it's a pretty big financial group.
那可是很大的财团啊
This is the first cruise ship built by Yashiro Shipbuilding Company at a cost of 100 million yen.
这可是八代造船公司花了1亿日元首次制造的游轮哦
It's gotta be luxurious!
如果不够豪华怎么行呢
Distinguished guests.
尊贵的客人
Are you Mr. Mouri?
请问您是毛利先生吗
Yes.
是的
We're preparing your seats right now.
现在为您准备座位
Please wait for a moment.
请稍候片刻
Professor.
博士
What's that?
那是什么
This?
这个啊
It's just a regular IC Recorder.
只是个普通的数位录音笔(IC Recorder)
I thought I could use it to record my thoughts when I get any ideas for new inventions.
我是想只要一有新发明的灵感就马上录下来
Oh, right.
对了
Speaking of new inventions...
说到新发明
Cufflink speakers.
袖扣型扬声器
It also has the ability to transmit sound.
还带有窃听功能
That's pretty cool.
挺时髦的嘛
Not bad.
这个不错啊
Cufflinks?
袖扣啊
That's great.
正好
I'll borrow them for a while.
暂时借我用用
But these are...
但是这个
Idiot!
笨蛋
These things are made for dashing men like me.
这种东西当然要配我这种时尚人士
It's too early for a brat like you.
你这样的小鬼还早呢
But...
但是
Dad,
爸爸
those are...
那是…
It's okay, Miss Ran.
算了 小兰姐姐
I probably don't need to use them inside this ship anyway.
反正在船上也用不到吧
Mr. Mouri.
毛利先生
You must be the famous detective, Mr. Kogoro Mouri, right?
是名侦探毛利小五郎先生吧
It's me.
是我
Great!
太好了
What's with this guy?
这家伙想干什么啊
I'm a script writer, Hironari Kusaka.
我是编剧 日下宽成
I'm a big fan of yours, Mr. Mouri.
是毛利先生的忠实崇拜者哦
So kind of you to say this.
那真是太感谢了
This is Miss Minako Akiyoshi.
这位是秋吉美波子小姐
She's the sub-leader of the design team for this cruise ship.
她是设计出这艘游轮的设计小组副组长
She was also the one who came up with its beautiful name "Aphrodite".
“阿芙洛狄忒号（Aphrodite）”这么好的名字也是她取的
I'm Akiyoshi.
我是秋吉
Nice to meet you.
请多多关照
I'm Mouri.
我是毛利
She's beautiful.
美女
Excuse me... Mr. Mouri...
那个 毛利先生
Sorry to keep you waiting.
让您久等了
Your seats have been prepared.
已经为您准备好了座位
Ah, sorry. Can you add two more seats?
对不起 能再加两个座位吗
You don't mind, right, Mr. Mouri?
可以的吧 毛利先生
Then, please follow me.
那么 请跟我来
Don't you think he's a bit strange?
不觉得大叔有点奇怪吗
Why?
为什么
If it were the usual him...
如果是平时的大叔的话
Speaking of Aphrodite,
说到阿芙洛狄忒
she is the goddess of love and beauty.
就是爱与美的女神
Compared to this boat,
比起船来
this name would be better suited for you.
这个名字和你更相配啊
That's what he would say, isn't it?
不是会这样说吗
Maybe it's because Miss Minako looks like my mother.
这也许是因为美波子小姐和我妈妈长得像吧
I see.
原来如此
Now that you've mentioned it, they do look alike.
这么说的话 还真是很像呢
In other words, she's the type that Mr. Mouri is unable to handle.
也就是说 是大叔搞不定的类型啦
In fact, I'm writing a drama based on a luxury cruise ship.
事实上 我正在写一部以豪华游轮为舞台的连续剧企划书
I met Miss Akiyoshi while I was interviewing her.
在采访的时候认识了秋吉小姐
Indeed.
是的
I see.
原来如此
By the way, Mr. Mouri, you were invited, right?
话说回来 毛利先生当然是被邀请来的吧
Or did they hire you to investigate something?
还是接受了某项委托什么的
How can I put this?
这个怎么说才好呢
Well, it's not like that.
那个 不是的
What does that mean?
不是的 是指…
The ones invited were actually Miss Sonoko's parents.
被邀请的其实是 这位园子小姐的父母
Her father is the president of Suzuki Group.
她的父亲是铃木财团的会长
But my parents couldn't make it.
但是我爸妈怎么也抽不出空来
So I came in their place.
于是我就代替他们来了
Then I thought the more the merrier.
反正也要来 叫上大家一起会比较开心啦
So the eight of us got invitations as well.
于是我们8个人也受到了邀请
So that's how it was.
原来是这么一回事啊
It's just like we're their substitutes.
就是类似于替补队员登场的情况啦
I see.
原来如此
I see...
原来是这样啊
By the way, what kind of story are you writing?
问你啊 你写的是什么故事呢
Is it about a one-week trip around the world on a luxury cruise ship?
乘坐豪华游轮环游世界一周吗
That sounds interesting.
听上去真不错
Yeah?
是吧
Maybe it's a story like the disast rous Titanic that sank on its maiden voyage.
可能是像泰坦尼克号一样处女航就沉没的灾难故事也说不定
Ai...
小哀
Speaking of sinking,
说到沉没的话
there was an accident where a Yashiro's cargo ship collided with an iceberg, right?
以前发生过八代造船的货轮和冰山相撞的事故吧
Yes, it was an accident during the winter 15 years ago.
是的 那是15年前的那个冬天的事情了
I heard it was due to the misjudgment of the captain.
原因似乎是船长的判断失误
One staff member died.
一名船员遇难
And the captain ended his life along with the ship.
船长也和船共存亡了
Really?
真的吗
What if this ship sinks too?
如果这艘船也沉没的话怎么办啊
I can only swim 7 meters.
我只能游7米啊
Don't worry.
不要紧的
The Aphrodite has a very good captain.
阿芙洛狄忒号的船长非常优秀
There are no icebergs around this part of the ocean.
这附近的海域也没有冰山
Anyway, if the ship sinks, the first people to be rescued will definitely be those people there.
船沉没的时候最先被救的肯定是那些人吧
Huh?
咦
Is that Mr. Niimi?
那难道是新见先生
The former Prime Minister?
前首相
And his wife.
还有他的太太
And then, the ones in show business...
然后是演艺界的…
Aren't those the Uruashi Sisters?
那不是丽姐妹吗
No matter where I see them, they always look so hot!
无论什么时候身材都那么火辣
Those people are all guests invited by the president of the Yashiro group.
那些人可都是八代会长的上宾啊
Speak of the devil.
说曹操曹操到
President Yashiro and his daughter have arrived.
八代会长父女出现了
After President Yashiro's daughter
八代家招赘了上门女婿后
got married, she succeeded her father and became the Chief of Yashiro Shipbuilding Company.
女儿贵江就继承父业当上了八代造船的社长
Speaking of which,
说起来
Chief Takae's husband
贵江社长的丈夫
died in a traffic accident not long ago.
就在前不久因交通事故去世了呢
He did?
是吗
Mr. Hideto Yashiro was my superior.
八代英人老师是我的上司
He was also the leader of this cruise ship's design team.
同时也是这艘游轮设计组的组长
I see.
是这样啊
I heard that while he was driving,
听说是在驾驶汽车的时候
he had a heart attack and drove off a cliff.
心脏病突发 从悬崖坠落了
It's the captain!
是船长先生
He's so cool!
好帅哦
He's Captain Wataru Kaidou.
他是海藤渡船长
Remember that accident 15 years ago
刚刚说到的那起
that we talked about earlier?
15年前的事故
He was the first-mate of that ship.
那时他是那艘船的副船长
What? It's suspicious?
什么 觉得可疑
About Hideto Yashiro's accident?
关于八代英人的意外死亡吗
Yes.
是
He happened to have a heart attack while going downhill.
正好在下坡的时候心脏病突发
That doesn't feel right.
总觉得有问题
But according to the local police's investigation, there wasn't anything suspicious, right?
但是根据当地警方的调查确实没有什么疑点吧
That's true, but...
虽然是这样没错
Fine.
好吧
It's not a bad thing to investigate until you're satisfied.
调查到自己能接受为止也没什么不好
I'll contact the local police there.
当地的警方那里 我来联系好了
Thank you so much.
拜托您了
Well, Officer Sato...
那个 佐藤警官
Do you need my help?
要我帮忙吗
You still haven't finished your report yet, have you?
你的报告还没写完吧
Chiba.
千叶
Give me a hand.
你来帮忙
Okay.
是
Well, since our drinks are all set...
那么 既然大家的杯子都已经斟满了
Let me do it, Mr. Mouri.
让我来吧 大叔
Then, to this pleasant cruise trip...
那么 为了这次快乐的游轮观光
and...
还有
to Ran, the winner of the Kanto Karate Tournament.
为了祝贺小兰在这次关东空手道大会上获得优胜
Cheers!
干杯
Thank you.
多谢
Sonoko, you were really...
园子你真是的
Miss Ran!
小兰姐姐
You're the winner of the karate tournament. That's amazing!
空手道大会优胜 好厉害啊
And it's the Kanto tournament!
而且还是关东大会哦
Awesome!
好厉害啊
Awesome, awesome!
厉害厉害
Did Kudo send you any gift to congratulate you?
工藤有没有送你什么贺礼啊
Shinichi?
新一
I told him on the phone.
电话里和他说了
He said, "Really? Not bad."
他说 是吗 不错啊
Is that all?
就这样吗
Anyway, he has been busy solving his cases.
反正他一天到晚总在忙破案
That deduction maniac.
那个推理狂
That was after I said congratulations a million times as Conan.
那可是在我用柯南的身份说了无数遍恭喜累得半死之后
I'm so full!
饱了饱了
The steak was really delicious.
好好吃哦 这个牛排
I wish I could have it everyday.
好想每天都吃呢
Next is dessert, right?
接下来是甜点吧
What's wrong?
怎么了
I feel a little seasick.
好像有点晕船了
Yeah, I'm a little dizzy too.
我也晕得一塌糊涂了
Dad, you drank too much alcohol!
爸爸你是酒喝多了
Ran, don't embarrass me.
真不给我面子啊
Geez...
真是的
Your father is interesting.
好有趣的爸爸啊
No, he's just an old alcoholic.
不 只是个醉鬼老头罢了
I'm sorry.
不好意思
I think I gotta go back and rest in my room.
我先告辞回房间休息去了
Are you okay?
不要紧吧
I have medicine in my room.
房间里面有药的
See you later.
再见
Take care of yourself.
多保重
Hold on,
对不起 打搅一下
Dad...
爸爸
Are you sure you're okay?
你真的不要紧吗
Kogoro Mouri
毛利小五郎
is A-OK, over!
不要紧 报告完毕
Don't worry, Miss Ran.
没问题的 小兰姐姐
All that's left is just to put him in bed to sleep.
接下来只要让他躺到床上睡觉就行了
Sorry.
对不起啊
Then, Conan...
那么 柯南
Can you take care of Dad for me?
爸爸就拜托你了
Professor, I'm really sorry about this.
博士 真是对不起啊
It's okay.
没关系的
It's okay, it's okay.
没关系没关系
Good night, Miss Ran.
晚安 兰兰
It's open, professor.
门开了 博士
Then, we're leaving too
那么 我们也走了
Then, Conan...
那么 柯南
Can you take care of Dad for me?
爸爸就拜托你了
Sorry to be disturbing you!
我们来打扰了
What are you guys doing all together?
在干什么呢 你们凑在一起
We're discussing what present we should give Miss Ran to celebrate her victory.
我们在讨论送什么礼物来庆祝小兰姐的优胜呢
What are these?
这是
Beautiful, right?
漂亮吧
We picked them up from the island we passed today.
是在白天经过的岛上捡回来的
We want to use them to make a gold medal for her!
把这个做成金牌送给她
Shinichi didn't prepare any gift. Miss Ran must be very sad.
新一哥哥什么礼物都没送 小兰姐姐也太可怜了吧
Good luck with that, then.
加油干哦
I'm going to take a bath.
我去洗澡了
Take a bath?
去洗澡吗
What? Want to join me?
怎么了 想一起洗吗
No... Thanks...
不…用了
Please allow me to confirm your schedule for tomorrow.
请允许我确认一下明天的行程
Your breakfast will be at 7:00 a.m. I'll bring a western-style meal set to your room.
早餐时间为上午7点 西式套餐将会送到您的房间
After that, the Chief will play squash with Mrs. Niimi from 9:00 a.m.
之后 社长从9点起和新见夫人打壁球
We have reserved a court on the 7th floor for you.
已经替您预约好了7楼的场地
After 30 minutes, the president will play billiards with Mr. Niimi.
会长在30分钟后和新见先生打台球
We've reserved the pool bar on the 3rd floor for you.
替您预约了3楼的台球吧（Pool Bar）
After the squash game, the Chief will return for a change of clothes at 9:30 a.m.
社长在壁球结束之后 9点半回房间更衣
This feels so good.
好舒服哦
Yeah, enjoying my morning tea in the salty breeze...
是啊 沐浴在海风中享受早茶
is really nice.
真是不错呢
Yeah, it's really nice.
真是不错
Very nice.
不错不错
This way, please.
请走这边
Okay.
好
Did you see? Chief Takae's beautiful legs?
看到了没 贵江社长的美腿
She really doesn't look like she's in her 50s!
一点都不像50多岁的人啊
Come on! How can you think of such things this early in the morning?
拜托 一大早就在这样 想干什么啊
Professor, it's about time, right?
博士 差不多了吧
Time for your classic lame riddles!
你特别拿手的冷笑话谜题
We know it's just a matter of time before you ask. Then ask us faster. We're already waiting!
反正总是要出 不快点说的话我们会一直坐立不安的
He's being humiliated by kids too.
这边也在被小孩子嘲笑啊
Okay, then. As you wish,
好 那么应各位的要求
I'll give you a riddle related to the cruise.
这次出和航海旅行有关的谜题
During the cruise, Genta has received some treatment at the medical room on the ship.
元太在航海当中 在船上的医疗室接受治疗
Which of the following illnesses does Genta have?
请问 元太得的是以下哪种病呢
1. He ate too much and hurt his stomach.
1、因为吃得太多把肚子吃坏了
2. He sprained his ankle after tripping.
2、跌倒扭伤了脚
3. He was out too long in the sun and got heat stroke.
3、日光浴晒过头 中暑了
Okay, which one is correct?
好了 正确答案是哪个呢
If it's the usual Genta, then it should be the first choice.
按常理来说 如果是元太的话应该是第1个答案
Wrong answer!
错了错了
It's not the first one, because I never hurt my stomach no matter how much I eat.
才不是第1个 因为我不管怎么吃都不会吃坏肚子的
I've figured it out.
我明白了
Me too.
我也猜出来了
But this riddle is too difficult for kids, isn't it?
可是这个问题给小孩猜太难了吧
Because English...
因为英语…
Sonoko!
园子
English? English is the hint?
英语吗 英语是提示呢
The second hint is ship (fune).
第2个提示是船
Ship (fune)?
船
I got it!
我知道了
It's the second one! He sprained his ankle.
答案是第2个扭伤脚
Fune in English is ship, right?
船在英语里是ship吧
And Genta put a medicine pack(shippu) on his ankle!
而元太的脚上贴了胶布（ship与胶布日语发音相近）
Correct.
正确
Also, "Yuujou" is friendship in English.
顺便说一下英语中友情是friendship
"Uwasabanashi" is gossip
闲话是gosship
It should be gossip, shouldn't it?
闲话（gossip）不是这样拼的吧
Then, we'll see each other at 10:00 a.m.
那么 就说好10点了
So ship refers to "shippu".
原来ship是指胶布啊
Say, Mitsuhiko...
我说啊 光彦
But if I sprain my ankle while crossing the sea(goukai), I'll regret(koukai) it, right?
但是航海时扭伤脚的话就会后悔哦（航海与后悔发音相近）
What does that mean?
这是什么呀
You're not as smart as I thought.
反应真是慢啊你
Oh right...
对了
When should we give her that present?
那个 什么时候送啊
We could give her now.
现在就可以啊
How about this?
这样做怎么样
Ran.
小兰
Let's go get one last round of drinks.
我们去拿最后一杯饮料吧
Okay.
好啊
I must drink as much as I want.
要好好喝个够
You've already drunk a lot.
你已经喝了不少了
This is just the beginning, all right?
还早呢 这算什么
We're going too!
我们也去
Let's go get some drinks!
喝点什么吧
What kind of juice is better?
喝哪种果汁比较好呢
Let's go!
走吧
Wait for me!
等等我
What are these kids so excited about?
这群小鬼吵些什么呢
Coming.
来了
I know the secret you've been hiding for 15 years.
15年前的秘密我已经知道了
At 10:15 a.m.,
10点15分
go to the basement marina.
请到地下船坞来
I see.
原来如此
The accident happened right outside of his villa.
现场真的就在离别墅不远的地方啊
Let's go check out his villa.
去别墅调查一下吧
Okay.
好了
What should we do now?
接下来干点什么呢
It's still a little cold to go for a swim.
游泳的话还有点冷呢
I'm going to change my clothes.
我要去换衣服了
Change?
换衣服
Actually, I got an invitation from the Uruashi Sisters.
其实 我接受了丽姐妹的邀请
They said they wanted to hear the stories of the famous detective Kogoro Mouri.
她们说是想听名侦探毛利小五郎的故事
See you later.
再见啦
He's really something, huh?
大叔还真能干啊
When did he get the invitation?
是什么时候约的啊
Let's forget about him.
不管他了
So, what do you want to do, guys?
那么 大家想干些什么呢
I want to play hide-and-seek.
我想玩捉迷藏
It seems like fun.
好像挺有趣的
Let's play!
一起玩吧
Hide-and-seek? How nostalgic.
捉迷藏啊 好怀念呢
We played it a lot when we were kids.
小时候经常玩啊
In the park and the vacant lands of the new community.
在公园里呀 新社区的空地里呀
I even played it in elementary school once.
在小学的时候也曾经玩过一次呢
Really?
是吗
Sorry, I'll pass.
不好意思 我不玩
Let's play together, Conan!
一起玩吧 柯南
You're always trying to be a lone wolf!
你这家伙真不合群
Come to think of it, I was rejected by Shinichi at that time too.
这么说来 那时候也被新一拒绝了
All right! Let's play hide-and-seek together!
好 一起玩吧 捉迷藏
I suppose it'll kill some time.
就当消磨时间吧
What about you, professor?
博士呢
I have made reservations for a massage.
我预约了按摩
What an old man!
真是个老头
So, here are the rules.
那么 接下来说一下规则
The time limit is 30 minutes.
规定时间为30分钟
The hiding area is from the first floor to the seventh floor,
从1楼到7楼都可以躲
excluding passenger cabins, employee-only areas, toilets and observation rooms.
但客舱 外人禁止入内的场所 厕所 观景浴室除外
How's that?
怎么样
Agreed!
赞成
Then, please gather around.
那么请大家围拢过来
Rock, paper, scissors!
石头 剪子 布
Okay, Sonoko is the seeker.
好 园子当鬼
Wait... Wait a minute.
等 等一下
No, no, no.
不行 不行
It's impossible to find 6 people in 30 minutes
在这么大的船上30分钟内要找到6个人
on such a big ship!
肯定不可能啦
Then, how about we make an exception, and add an extra seeker?
那就作为特别规则 再加个鬼吧
So we'll have two seekers?
鬼有两个的吗
It doesn't matter. Just change the rules.
无所谓啦 改一下规则嘛
Then, let's play rock, paper and scissors again!
那么再猜一次拳吧
I hope we'll work well together.
请多指教了
So do I.
彼此彼此
What a unique combination.
真是有特色的组合
Right...
对了
Can I borrow your detective badge?
你的侦探徽章 借用一下
Why?
为什么啊
If there are two seekers, it will be hard to know who's been caught, right?
有两个鬼的话 谁已经被抓住就不知道了
We need to use these badges to communicate.
我们要用这个徽章取得联系呀
Don't lose it.
可别弄丢了
Then, 5 minutes left. We'll start at 9:50 a.m.
那么5分钟后 从9点50分开始找
If the seekers find everyone by 10:20 a.m., the seekers win.
10点20分前找全5个人 鬼就赢了
Okay, we won't lose.
OK 不会输的
Too bad, but we'll win.
很遗憾 我们赢定了
Because...
因为…
We have Conan.
我们有柯南在
You think too highly of me.
你还真看得起我
Okay, let's go.
好 出发吧
Hurry up and hide!
快点躲起来呀
We're going.
先走了
Wait for me! I'll find you one by one.
等着我把你们一个个揪出来
Miss Ran hasn't noticed it yet.
小兰姐姐好像还没有发现
She'll notice it while we're playing hide-and-seek.
玩捉迷藏时一定会发现的啦
She'll be surprised!
肯定会吃惊的
Yes.
好
I got it!
拿到了
Oh no!
糟了
I guess this isn't a good place.
这里不行啊
What time does the movie start?
电影几点开始来着
It's at 10:00 a.m., right?
是10点吧
We gotta go now.
得快走了
Hurry up.
赶快赶快
It's going to start.
要开始了
Too bad.
不妙了
Yes!
好
I never thought I'd be the seeker.
没想到居然是我当鬼
But, it's not bad to be on the seeker once in a while.
但偶尔做做找人的角色也不错啊
Five minutes have passed.
5分钟已经到了
I'll look from the 5th floor and up.
那么 我负责找5楼以上
I'll leave the lower floors to you, all right?
下面的就拜托你了
All right.
好
Hey, Kudo!
喂 工藤
Haibara.
灰原
I guess you don't even realize you're playing hide-and-seek, do you?
你一点都没有意识到自己是在玩捉迷藏吧
Okay, I got one.
好 找到一个
How did you know?
你怎么知道的啊
Of course a food lover would hide at a restaurant.
馋鬼躲藏的地方通常都是餐厅
Haibara...
灰原
You borrowed it from the professor, right?
是向博士借的吧
This is exactly being too smart for your own good.
这就叫聪明反被聪明误了
All right, come on out.
好了好了 出来吧
I thought this was a good hiding place.
我还认为这是个躲藏的好地方呢
Not at all. You're still 10 years too early to beat me.
还差得远呢 要想赢我起码还要再过10年
Hello, this is Akiyoshi.
喂 我是秋吉
Miss Minako, it's Kusaka.
美波子小姐 我是日下
Then, to get right to the point, let's start with the list of characters.
那么言归正传 从登场人物名单开始
Nanami Okazaki,
冈崎奈奈美
age 20.
20岁
Served as an attendant on the luxury cruise Southern Cross.
曾在豪华游轮南十字星座号（Southern Cross）任服务员
Next, I'll read the story.
接下来 我念故事情节
Nanami Okazaki loves the sea.
冈崎奈奈美非常热爱大海
Maybe it's because she was born and raised by the sea.
或许是因为在海边土生土长的缘故
She loves its vastness more than anything else.
她喜欢大海的宽广胜于其他任何东西
Although we've easily found the four of them...
虽然很顺利的找到了4个人
As expected, the last one turned out to be the hardest one.
果然剩下的是那个最难对付的
Is Miss Ran so good at hiding?
小兰姐这么擅长捉迷藏吗
She's like a ninja, a ninja!
简直就是忍者 忍者啊
Would an ordinary elementary school kid climb on ceilings and dive in ponds?
一般的小学生会贴在天花板上 潜在池塘里吗
Ceilings?
天花板
Ponds?
池塘里吗
Amazing!
好厉害啊
She's had a lot of stamina since she was a kid.
她从小体力就好得很
12 minutes left. Let's keep looking for her.
还有12分钟 继续找吧
This isn't the right place either.
这里也不对啊
10:11 a.m.
10点11分
Only 9 minutes left...
只剩下9分钟了呀
Hello! It's me, Mouri!
我来拜访了 我是毛利
I'll avenge my father's death!
我要为父亲报仇
I'm starting the countdown.
开始倒计时
5 seconds left.
还剩5秒
We won in hide-and-seek!
捉迷藏 我们赢了
It's all thanks to ninja Miss Ran!
多亏了忍者小兰姐啊
Right, right!
是啊是啊
Miss Ran!
小兰姐姐
I told you we'd win, right?
果然是我们赢了吧
Where were you hiding, Miss Ran?
小兰姐姐藏在哪里了
You were kicking the soccer ball the entire time, right?
柯南刚才一直在踢足球吧
I knew it all along.
我可知道得一清二楚哦
It seems like Miss Ran hasn't noticed it yet.
小兰姐姐好像还是没有发现
That's strange.
奇怪啊
Maybe s he's too slow.
太迟钝了吧
Is she still looking?
她难道还在找
What?
什么
So cold.
好冷
What's going on?
怎么回事
A box?
箱子
Am I in a box?
我在箱子里吗
No! Someone help me!
不要 来人啊
Somebody! Please help me!
有人吗 快来救我
Help! Help!
救命啊
Help me!
快来救我
What?
什么
What happened, Miss Sonoko?
怎么了 园子姐姐
Help me!
快来救我
Calm down, Sonoko.
冷静点 园子
Where are you now?
你现在在哪里
A box! I'm in a box!
箱子 我在箱子里
Hold on, Sonoko, I can't hear you.
等一下 园子 听不清楚
Say it again.
再说一次
Did the batteries die?
没电了吗
Damn. It was because...
完了 是那个时候
You're cold, Sonoko?
觉得冷吗 园子
Freezing?
冷冰冰的
If so...
这样的话
It's the freezer!
是冷冻库
What are you doing?
干什么啊 你们
Where is the freezer?
冷冻库在哪里
The freezer?
冷冻库
Please, my friend is in danger.
求求你 我朋友有危险了
It's on the second basement floor.
在地下2层
There are so many!
有好多啊
Which one is it?
是哪间
Let's split up and find her.
我们分头找
Okay.
好
Miss Sonoko.
园子姐姐
Sonoko?
园子
Are you there?
你在吗
Miss Sonoko?
园子姐姐
Where are you?
你在哪里
She's not here.
不在这里
Let's go outside.
出去吧
It's freezing.
冷死了
Where is she?
在哪里啊
Sonoko... Sonoko...
园子 园子
Damn it! Where?
可恶 在哪里
Where is she?
到底在哪
Could it be that... she's already dead?
难不成 已经死了
Don't say such unlucky things!
不要说不吉利的话
But there isn't any other place that's cold, is there?
但是 没有其他会让人变冷的地方啊
Dead?
死了
It's there!
是那里了
This ship has a place like this?
船上居然还有这种地方
It's surprising.
真令人吃惊
It's heavy.
好重啊
Sonoko!
园子
Take her to the sick bay immediately!
快送她去医疗室
I'm alive again.
复活了
There's no need to worry.
不用担心了
Just keep her body warm.
只要这样让身体保持温暖
After a little more rest, she'll be able to move around.
再静养一会儿就可以活动了
Thank you.
谢谢您了
Thank god, Sonoko.
太好了 园子
But...
不过
Who would play this kind of prank?
是谁这样恶作剧呢
Prank?
恶作剧
This is not a prank.
这可不是恶作剧
This is an attempted murder.
是确确实实的杀人未遂
Please call the police immediately.
请马上报警
Got it.
明白了
Tell me more details.
把情况详细说一遍
Where were you attacked?
在哪里被袭击的
At the basement marina.
是在地下船坞
When I was there to look for Ran,
我去那里找小兰
I was suddenly hit on my shoulder by a stick or something.
突然被棍棒什么的击中肩膀
Then I passed out.
然后我就昏过去了
What about the face of the attacker?
那犯人的长相呢
I think I saw it,
好像是看到了
but I can't remember.
可是我记不起来了
And the time?
时间呢
I remember that.
这个我记得
It was at 10:11 a.m.
是10点11分
10:11 a.m.
10点11分
I see.
原来如此
The mortuary is only a few feet away from this place.
这里的话 和太平间真是近在咫尺
But why was Miss Sonoko attacked?
可是为什么园子姐姐会遭到袭击呢
This is...
这是
President Yashiro's metallic fan.
是八代会长的铁扇
Why would it be in such a place?
为什么会掉在这种地方
He's not in the room.
不在房间里
Mr. Mouri!
毛利先生
The captain talked to the police...
船长和员警联系过了
This is President Yashiro's room.
这里是八代会长的房间
The Uruashi Sisters told me that earlier.
刚才丽姐妹已经告诉我了
Come to think of it, someone came out of this room just now.
对了 刚才好像有人从这个房间出来
What do you mean by someone?
有人是什么意思
I couldn't see his face.
没能看到脸
Because he was wearing a windbreaker with a hood.
因为他穿着风衣还戴上了帽子
When was that?
什么时候
It was around 10:15 a.m.
是10点15分左右
Is that true, Mr. Mouri?
是真的吗 毛利先生
That's strange.
那就奇怪了
Neither of them wore a windbreaker.
那两位都没穿风衣
Chief Takae should be the only one in the room at that time.
这个时间应该只有贵江社长一个人在房间里才对
The purpose of wearing a windbreaker with a hood in the hallway was to hide his or her face, wasn't it?
在走廊里还要特的戴上风衣的帽子简直就像是为了遮住脸嘛
Could something have happened to the Chief?
难道社长她出事了
Chief!
社长
It's Tsujimoto!
我是辻本
You have a master key, right?
你有船上的总钥匙吧
But...
可是
Chief! Sorry for intruding!
社长 打扰了
Chief!
社长
Don't move!
别动
Stay here.
待在这里
How could this happen?
怎么这样
Who would do this?
到底是谁
I'm afraid she's been dead for 30 minutes.
恐怕已经死去30分钟了
I'll go and tell the captain.
我去通知船长
I'll go to the president.
我去通知会长
Looks like she was killed just after she came out of the bathroom.
刚从浴室出来就遭了毒手吗
The blood on this side has been wiped clean.
这里的血迹被擦拭过
Why?
为什么
Why only the blood on this side?
为什么只有这里的血迹
What the hell are you doing?
你这家伙在干什么
It hurts.
好痛
Geez!
真是的
Mr. Mouri!
毛利先生
Mr. Niimi said that President Yashiro left the billiard room and never came back.
新见先生说八代会长在打台球的中途离开后就一去不回了
What did you say?
你说什么
Maybe President Yashiro is in some trouble as well.
说不定八代会长也已经被卷入了某起事件之中
Thanks for coming!
来了
Mr. Mouri!
毛利先生
Thank you for coming, inspector.
辛苦您了 警官
Where's President Yashiro?
八代会长的行踪呢
He's still nowhere to be found.
仍然不明
The crew split up and searched the entire ship.
船员们已经分头在船内寻找过了
Anyway, whether in the air or on the waters,
不管怎么说 无论是天空还是海洋
wherever you go, cases follow you, right, Mr. Mouri?
只要有毛利先生的地方事件就接连不断的发生呢
Will it be in space next time?
下次会在宇宙吗
Go there by a rocket?
坐上火箭
How is that possible?
这怎么可能
What?
什么
The president's fingerprints?
会长的指纹
Yes.
是的
Most of them were found near the hatch of the basement marina where the blood was discovered.
在发现血迹的地下船坞出入口附近集中发现了大量指纹
Of course, the blood near the hatch matched that of President Yashiro.
当然 出入口的血迹和八代会长的血型是一致的
Thank you.
辛苦你了
Keep up the good work.
请继续工作吧
Also, inspector.
还有 警官
According to the staff at the basement marina,
根据地下船坞的工作人员所说
the hatch appeared to have been opened.
那个出入口的舱门有被开闭过的痕迹
And it was just a short time ago.
而且就在不久之前
What?
什么
Fingerprints,
指纹
bloodstains.
血迹
And the opened hatch.
舱门的开闭
If so, inspector, I'm afraid...
这样的话 警官 恐怕是…
I'm afraid President Yashiro was attacked by someone in the basement marina,
恐怕是八代会长在地下船坞遭到什么人的袭击后
and was pushed into the sea through the hatch.
从出入口被推下了大海
I believe we can safely assume that.
这样想应该没错吧
Maybe you're right.
可能就是这样
Shiratori.
白鸟
Contact the Coast Guard.
你去和海上保安厅联系
Ask for a sweep of the surrounding waters.
委托他们搜索附近的海域
Got it.
明白
Takagi!
高木
Yes, sir.
在
I want to ask the Niimi couple a few questions.
我想问新见夫妇几句话
Bring them here.
把他们带来
Yes, sir!
是
Then, Conan.
那么柯南
We'll take care of the rest.
接下去就交给我们
You return to your room.
你回房间去吧
Don't go outside unnecessarily.
避免不必要的外出
The murderer is probably still on this ship.
因为杀人犯很有可能还在船上
Okay.
知道了
There's a cake too.
还有蛋糕啊
It looks delicious.
看上去好好吃
Roast beef...
烤牛肉
I suppose it's okay to eat it one in a while...
偶尔吃一次没关系吧
Not even once in a while.
偶尔也不行
Oh right, professor...
对了博士
How about we bring Miss Ran and Miss Sonoko's meals to them?
我们把小兰姐和园子姐的给她们送过去吧
They must be hungry too.
她们两个肯定也饿了
No, it's better to leave Sonoko to the doctors.
不 园子的话还是交给医生负责比较好
Miss Ran also said she'd eat later, so don't worry about it.
小兰姐姐也说了她过会儿再来吃 不要紧的
Is that so?
是吗
Mitsuhiko.
光彦
Do you think she found the gold medal?
你说金牌被发现了吗
I don't think Miss Ran has the time to think about this kind of thing now.
小兰姐现在根本顾不过来吧
You have a point.
也是啊
Where is Conan?
柯南呢
Now that you've mentioned it, he's not here...
说起来确实不在呢
Did he leave us behind and went to help the police with the case again?
难道又抢先我们一步去配合警方做调查了
Maybe so.
也许是呢
He seems to be very good at this kind of hide-and-seek.
他玩这种捉迷藏似乎很在行呢
Thank you for your cooperation.
多谢配合
I probably don't need to say this, but please find the culprit as soon as possible.
虽然不用我们多说 但还是希望你们能早点找到犯人
Now then.
接下来
If Chief Takae returned to her room after the squash game
如果贵江社长是在打完壁球后回到房间里
and got killed after taking a bath,
洗澡后被杀害的话
then we can safely say that the person wearing the windbreaker
这样和毛利老弟擦肩而过的那个穿风衣的人
who passed by Mouri must be the culprit.
应该可以确定他就是犯人了
After that, the suspect went to the basement marina,
那个疑犯随后直接到了地下船坞
and murdered President Yashiro, who had an appointment with that person there.
再杀害了事先约到那里见面的八代会长的话
In that case, the timing matches.
时间上也正好吻合
That means...
也就是说
these two cases were most likely done by the same culprit.
这两起事件的犯人是同一个人的可能性很大
Mouri.
毛利
What about the culprit's physical stature?
犯人的体形如何
This person was about 170 cm tall.
身高1米70左右
And seemed pretty skinny.
是苗条的瘦长型
We can't tell whether this person is a male or female just by the height.
光从身高无法判断是男性还是女性呢
Come to think of it, the murdered Chief Takae was about the same height as well.
说起来好像和被杀害的贵江社长身高差不多
Miss Tsujimoto.
辻本小姐
You sure this is that windbreaker?
这就是那件风衣吗
Yes.
是的
Each passenger was given one as a souvenir for being on this ship.
作为乘船纪念品给每位乘客都发了一件
But if they really wanted to, it would be easy for the crew to get one, right?
可是只要想拿的话船员也很容易弄到手吧
Shiratori,
白鸟
s peaking of the culprit's motives...
关于犯人的动机
I believe it was an act of revenge.
应该是为了报仇吧
The victim's wallet and jewelry were still there.
因为被害人的钱包和珠宝都还在
There were no sighs of the lock being picked.
房门的锁没有被撬动的痕迹
Either the victim opened the door and let the culprit in,
恐怕是被害人开门让犯人进去
or the culprit had a master key and sneaked in.
或者是犯人持有总钥匙自己开门偷偷进去
These are the only two possibilities.
这两种可能之一
Mr. Misaki, who holds the master keys?
岬先生 哪些人持有总钥匙呢
There are quite a few.
有不少人呢
Including me, of course.
我当然有
And the guards, Natsuhi who took care of the Chief,
警卫和负责照顾社长他们的夏帆
and the attendants in charge of the guest rooms.
还有负责管理客房的服务员们
They all have keys.
大家都有
I see.
原来如此
Inspector.
警官
The culprit targeted the victim when she was alone.
犯人瞄准的是被害人落单的时候
In that case, is it possible that the culprit knew the victim's schedule?
这样的话犯人是不是事先就知道被害人的行程安排呢
Miss Tsujimoto.
辻本小姐
You were the one in charge of their schedules, right?
负责两人的行程安排的就是你吧
Right.
是的
Who else knew about their schedules?
其他还有什么人知道这个行程安排的
Except the chief purser Mr. Misaki,
我除了对乘务长岬先生说过
I never told anyone.
没有向其他人泄露
That is to say,
也就是说
if you were 10cm taller,
如果你再高10cm
or if Mr. Misaki's weight was 10kg less,
或者岬先生再瘦10Kg的话
you two would become the most suspicious ones.
就变成最有嫌疑的人了
There's one more thing.
还有一件事
Whether Sonoko's incident
发生在园子身上的事件
has anything to do with these two cases.
不知道是否和这两起事件有关
Come to think of it,
说起来
you passed by the suspect,
和疑犯擦肩而过
and didn't even see the suspect's face...
居然连长相都没有看到
Yeah... that's embarrassing.
真是丢人啊
But inspector...
可是警官
This place is a closed room above the ocean.
这里是大海上的密室
The culprit must be somewhere on this ship.
犯人肯定还在这艘船上
That means, including the passengers and crew, there are only 600 suspects here, right?
那就是说乘客船员加起来只不过有600个嫌疑犯而已
Anyway, Takagi...
总之 高木
Keep questioning the passengers and see if there are any other witnesses.
你继续在乘客中调查看有没有其他的目击者
Yes, sir.
是
Mr. Misaki and Miss Tsujimoto.
岬先生和辻本小姐
Please tell us more about the passengers and crew.
请给我们仔细介绍一下乘客和船员的情况
Understood.
知道了
Just like Officer Shiratori said,
的确如白鸟警官所说
when did the culprit know about the Yashiro family's schedule?
犯人是什么时候得知了八代父女的行程安排呢
Miss Natsuhi said she didn't tell anyone.
夏帆小姐说她没有对任何人说过
That is...
那个是
That's right. If someone used that...
对了 说不定只要用那个
I have something to ask Miss Natsuhi!
我有事要请问那个大姐姐
Conan!
柯南
Where did you come from, brat?
小鬼 你从哪里钻出来的
Did you talk about today's schedule in the president's room last night?
昨天晚上你有没有在会长的房间里对他们说今天的行程安排啊
When I sent them back to the suite after dinner,
晚饭后我把他们送回房间时
I confirmed the schedule with them both.
和他们两位确认了一下行程
Then, was there any time yesterday when no one was in the president's room?
那么昨天会长的房间有没人的时候吗
Let me see...
这个啊
Yesterday, President Yashiro said he was tired,
昨天八代会长说他累了
he was resting in his room until dinner.
晚饭前都在房间里休息
The only time the room was empty was during dinner.
房间里没人的时候就只有吃晚饭的这段时间
I see.
原来如此
You little brat...
小鬼
You've been listening to our conversation, haven't you?
你一直在偷听我们的讲话吧
Ouch!
痛 痛
Mr. Misaki!
岬先生
Was there any passenger who didn't come to dinner?
有没有乘客没来吃晚饭的
No, I believe all of them were there.
没有 应该是全体出席的
If so, the culprit should be one of the crew members.
这样的话犯人就是船员了
I'm sorry, I think I gotta go back and rest in my room.
不好意思 我先告辞回房间去休息了
Were you interviewed by Mr. Kusaka?
大姐姐有没有接受过日下先生的采访
Mr. Hironari Kusaka?
日下宽成先生吗
Yes, I have.
有啊
Then did any master key go missing after that?
那随后有没有发现总钥匙遗失了
Don't go too far.
不要太过分了
How could that happen?
怎么可能有这种事
Well, actually...
那个 其实
About 3 weeks ago,
大概3个星期前
we found that one of them was gone.
发现有1把不见了
It really happened?
有这种事啊
Furthermore, just as Conan said,
而且和柯南说的一样
it was right after the interview with Mr. Kusaka.
就在接受了日下先生的采访之后
Wait a minute.
稍等一下
Who is it?
是谁啊
I mean that Mr. Kusaka.
那个日下先生
He's a script writer.
是个编剧
He has been here many times for interviews.
来采访过好几次了
I see...
原来如此
So, Conan...
那么柯南
Is there anything suspicious about that person?
那人有什么可疑的地方吗
Mr. Kusaka returned to his room in the middle of dinner.
日下先生晚饭吃到一半就先回房间了
He said he was seasick.
他说他晕船
I was thinking he might be hiding in the president's room and eavesdropping.
可是我想他会不会是偷偷躲进会长的房间去偷听了呢
Idiot! He's not a kid like you!
笨蛋 又不是你这种小鬼
He wouldn't be hiding in there.
怎么会做这种捉迷藏般的事情
A bug.
窃听器
Maybe he left a listening device in the president's room at that time.
说不定他趁那个时候在会长的房间里装了窃听器
I see.
原来如此
What do you think, Mouri?
怎么样 毛利
What's that Mr. Kusaka's physical stature?
那位日下先生的体型如何
Come to think of it, it does resemble the culprit's.
这么一说似乎挺像的
All right, let's meet Mr. Kusaka.
好 让我们见一下那位日下先生
I see... A listening device...
原来如此 窃听器啊
As expected of the famous detective Kogoro Mouri.
真不愧是名侦探毛利小五郎
Not like that. This time it was thanks to Conan's idea,
不 这次是在柯南的启发下
and we did a bit of reasoning.
我们自己推理出来的
Is that so?
是这样啊
But this reasoning is not correct.
不过这个推理可不对哦
Because at 10:15 a.m.,
因为10点15分的时候
I was on the phone with Miss Minako in this room.
我正在这个房间里和美波子小姐打电话呢
Miss Minako? That designer?
美波子小姐 就是那个设计师吗
Because I couldn't use my cell phone at sea.
因为在海上手机不能用
So I used this phone.
就用了这个电话
The exact time you were on the phone is...
通话时间是
From 10:00 a.m., it lasted about 30 minutes.
10点开始打了30分钟左右
Just check out the phone records and you'll know the exact time, right?
只要查一下通话记录不就能知道准确的时间了吗
Then what was the phone call about?
那么电话的内容是
If you don't mind.
如果方便的话
I was just done writing the script draft.
我刚写好的企划书
So I thought I could get her opinions on it.
想听一下她的感想
Script draft?
企划书
The draft for a drama based on a luxury cruise ship.
以豪华游轮为舞台的连续剧企划书
She once gave me advice about cruise ships.
她曾经给过我游轮方面的建议
Cruising Love Story.
游轮之旅恋爱物语
I even specially asked for a single room,
我还特地的要了单人房
so that I could finish this without being disturbed by anyone else.
就是为了不受任何人打扰完成这个
But why didn't you see her in person to talk about it.
可是为什么不直接见面说呢
After all, you're on the same ship.
明明在同一艘船上
Because she's still single.
因为她还是单身啊
It's inappropriate to visit her room.
去她房间拜访总是不太好
If at a cafe or a lounge, there could be someone listening to us.
如果在咖啡厅休息室什么的可能又会被人听到
Stealing of ideas happens quite often
创意被剽窃的事情可是屡见不鲜的
in my line of work.
在我们这一行里
I see.
原来是这样啊
From what I can see, Mr. Kusaka is innocent.
凭我的感觉 日下先生是清白的
We don't know until we confirm his alibi.
在不在场证明没得到确认之前还不知道呢
I'm thirsty.
我觉得口渴了
Then let's hurry up.
那我们快点走吧
What's wrong, Mr. Mouri?
怎么了 毛利先生
I think that lady must've caught his eye.
是被刚才的女性吸引住了吧
She was quite beautiful, after all.
因为是个挺不错的美女嘛
I've heard about the case from Mr. Misaki.
岬先生对我说了案件的情况
It's true that Mr. Kusaka called at precisely 10:00 a.m.
日下先生确实在10点整来过电话
We talked for about 30 minutes.
和他说了大概有30分钟
He came to ask for my advice on his script draft before.
之前他就来和我商量过关于企划书的事情
So this morning, when we drank tea,
在早上喝茶的时候
he said he was going to finish the story soon,
他就说故事情节马上要写好了
and he wanted to hear my opinion.
想听一下我的意见
He said he would call me at 10 a.m.,
10点钟会打电话给我
and told me to wait in the room at that time.
让我准时等在房间里
I see.
是这样啊
As long as we can confirm that.
只要这件事能确认就可以了
Thank you for your time.
谢谢 打扰了
I guess Mr. Kusaka's alibi has been confirmed.
这样一来日下先生的不在场证明就成立了
As long as those two are not accomplices.
如果那两人不是共犯的话
The phone in his room isn't a wireless phone.
房间里的电话也不是无线电话
Which means, he couldn't arrive at the crime scene while speaking on the phone.
不可能一边打电话一边赶到案发现场
What's up, Mr. Mouri?
又怎么了 毛利先生
You're thinking about Minako, right?
是在想美波子小姐吧
After all, she's a beautiful woman too.
因为她也是个少见的美人啊
From the above...
以上的…
Mr. Tome!
利目先生
Inspector Megure.
目暮警官
How's the investigation going?
调查得怎么样
We're mostly done.
大致上都调查完了
There isn't anything special.
没有其他收获
Is that so?
这样啊
But there were traces of reddish brown liquid wiped off on the floor near the body.
但是在尸体附近的地板上有红褐色液体被擦去的痕迹
Reddish brown liquid?
红褐色液体
Mr. Tome.
利目先生
Wasn't that blood?
那个不是血迹吗
No.
不是
The color looks similar,
虽然颜色很像
but it didn't respond like blood.
但是没有检测出血液反应
Then what was it?
那么是…
Inspector Megure.
目暮警官
I've questioned all the passengers and crew members on the 6th floor.
我询问过6楼所有的乘客和船员了
We haven't found any witnesses.
没有找到目击者
I see.
这样啊
The welcome party starts at 5:00 p.m.
欢迎晚宴是5点开始吧
Before that, let's split up and ask the other passengers.
在此之前我们还是分头去问一下其他乘客吧
Yes, sir.
是
Then, inspector.
那么警官
We'll go back to headquarters with the evidence we've collected.
我们带着采集到的证据回总部去了
Thank you for your hard work.
辛苦你了
Excuse me!
大姐姐
I've been looking for you.
让我找了好久哦
Can I ask another question?
我能再问个问题吗
Sure, Mr. Little Detective.
可以啊 小侦探先生
What do you want to ask?
想问什么呢
What was your phone call with Mr. Kusaka like?
和日下先生通的电话是怎样的
Well...
这个啊
How should I put it?
怎么说才好呢
He was reading the story and I was just listening.
他念故事而我只是听而已
Just listening?
只是听而已吗
If I interrupted, he'd get angry.
如果中间插嘴的话他会生气的
He would say, "Please be quiet".
他会说 请安静的?
That's why I don't usually interrupt him.
所以 一般我是不会乱插嘴的
Then, until Mr. Kusaka finished the story,
那在日下先生念完故事之前
you were just listening in silence?
你一直沉默的听着吗
Yes.
没错
After about 20 minutes, when the story was finally finished,
大约过了20分钟 故事念完后
he asked me how it was.
他问我觉得怎么样
Then I told him it was interesting.
我才回答他说很有趣啊
It's done.
完成了
Here.
给你
Thank you...
谢…谢谢
Are you feeling better, Sonoko?
感觉好点了吗 园子
I'm fine now.
已经没事了
We shouldn't have played hide-and-seek if we knew it would be like this.
早知道这样就不玩什么捉迷藏了
Don't say that.
别这么说
Speaking of which...
说起来
Before we started playing hide-and-seek...
在开始捉迷藏前
Too bad, but we'll win.
我们赢定了
Because...
因为…
What were you going to say after that?
那之后你本来想说什么
Didn't I tell you I played hide-and-seek once during elementary school?
我不是说过小学时也玩过捉迷藏吗
That was during the school open day when I was in first grade.
那是在小学1年级校园开放日的时候
I asked Shinichi to come play at that time, but...
虽然那时也有叫新一一起来玩
Shinichi, are you listening?
新一 你在听吗
Shinichi...
新一
Let's play hide-and-seek.
一起玩捉迷藏吧
It's fun!
很好玩的哦
Sorry, but I'll pass.
不好意思 我不玩
The soccer game is coming up.
就快要足球比赛了
That cocky brat!
狂妄的家伙
He's been acting like that since he was a kid?
那家伙还是小鬼的时候就这副德性了啊
After that, we decided to play without Shinichi.
后来 我们就在没有新一的情况下玩
Under the stage in the gym, there was a space used to store things, remember?
在体育馆的舞台下 不是有收纳物品的空间吗
There were many folding play mats and other stuff, right?
记得是放折叠垫子什么的吧
On the side of the stage, there was also a small space behind the stairs.
舞台侧面的梯子之后也有狭小的空间
So you hid in there?
你就躲在那里面啊
I thought if I hid there, no one would find me.
我想躲在那里一定不会被发现的
Then the teacher who came to check on things pushed the stairs back.
随后来巡视的老师把梯子推了回去
I couldn't get out.
我就出不去了
Then what happened?
后来呢
No one could find me,
大家怎么找都找不到我
and I couldn't get out. So I didn't know what to do.
而我又出不去 不知该怎么办
But Shinichi found me easily.
但是 新一轻而易举地就找到我了
On the way home, I asked Shinichi how he knew I was hiding there.
回家的路上 我就问新一怎么知道我藏在那里的
The Monster in School.
学校的妖怪
In that movie,
那部电影里
the kids who hid in the school building were all eaten by the monster, right?
藏在校舍里的孩子们都被妖怪吃掉了不是吗
That means, the chance of you hiding in the school building would be zero.
也就是说 你藏在校舍里的可能性为零
Wait a minute, how did you know I watched that movie?
等一下 你怎么知道我看过那部电影呢
Every time you passed by that video store,
每次路过租片的小店门口时
you always glanced at the movie poster.
你总会瞄一眼那张电影海报
Even though you always say you're afraid of monsters,
你嘴上说害怕妖怪
I know you'll definitely watch those movies.
那种电影却一定会去看的
So, the only place you could hide would be somewhere outside the school building.
这么一来 你能躲的地方就在校舍以外了
You like animals,
喜欢动物的你
so you wouldn't hide in the hen house, because that would scare the chickens.
也不会躲在小鸡窝里惊动小鸡
At that time, the seniors in the basketball club were organizing the sports equipment.
那时篮球部的高年级生在整理体育用品
If you were hiding in the sports equipment room, you wouldn't have gotten stuck there.
如果躲在体育用品室的话你不可能出不来
The pool is currently under construction.
游泳池目前正在施工中
So all that's left is the gym.
只剩下体育馆了
That's why I figured you were there.
所以我就认定是在那里了
I remember that, during PE class,
你好像有在体育馆上课时
you peeked behind the stairs once, right?
偷偷看过梯子后面吧
How's that? Surprised?
怎么样 惊呆了吧
So you've been watching me all along, Shinichi?
原来新一你一直都在注意我啊
You idiot, I haven't.
笨蛋 我才没有呢
Your're blushing.
脸红了哦
What are you talking about?
你说什么啊
It's because of the sunset.
是因为夕阳啦
Okay, okay, I finally understand.
好了好了 我总算明白了
When you said "It's the same as that time" yesterday, you were referring to this, huh?
昨天你说的和那时一样是指这事啊
Then, what you said at that time should be...
那么 那个时候的台词应该是
We'll win.
我们赢定了
Because...
因为
the only one who can find me is Shinichi.
能找到我的只有新一一个嘛
Am I right?
我说得没错吧
It's not like that!
才不是这样的啦
You're blushing!
脸红了哦
What are you talking about?
胡说什么啊
It's because of the sunset.
是因为夕阳啦
Mr. Mouri...
叔叔
What did he find Kusaka for?
他去找日下干什么
Coming.
来了
So it's you this time, boy.
这回换小鬼来了
I came to play.
我是来玩的
I took a look at this earlier. It's really a cool laptop!
刚才瞄了一眼觉得这台电脑可真棒呢
I use it to work.
它可是我的饭碗啊
This is not something for kids to read.
这不是小孩子看的东西
Okay.
知道了
It's the same as professor's.
咦 和博士的一样呢
Why can't I hear anything?
咦 怎么没声音呢
Brat.
小鬼
Get out.
出去吧
Not surprising, he won't keep the evidence forever.
不可能一直留着证据吧
Our hard-earned trip turned out to be a disaster.
难得的旅行就这样泡汤了
Don't say that, Genta.
不可以这样讲啊 元太
This is a serious case.
这次的事件很严重呢
I see.
这样啊
But why do humans always have to hurt each other?
但是 人为什么总是要相互伤害呢
If only we could all live in harmony.
大家要是都能和睦的生活就好了
That's impossible.
不可能
Because humans have emotions.
因为人是有情感的
Something invisible and fickle,
那是眼睛看不见而且善变的
something hard to deal with.
难以应付的东西
If it's friendship and love, then that's fine.
如果是友情和爱情还好
But if there's some setback
要是遇到什么挫折
that turns it into jealousy or hatred,
变成嫉妒或者仇恨的话
thoughts of murder will come along.
就会萌生杀意
But my Mom and Dad always fight with each other, but they still get along well.
可我的妈妈和爸爸总是吵架却还是很要好啊
That's because they can understand each other.
那是因为他们能互相体谅对方并为对方着想
Ai was right.
小哀说得没错
Humans always hurt others or get hurt by others over trivial matters.
人总是为了一些小事伤害着别人或被别人伤害着
If you want to stop it from happening,
要避免它发生
you must have a kind heart and be able to empathise.
必须要拥有一颗能体谅别人的心
Empathise?
能体谅别人的心
Professor!
博士
I want to borrow something from you, professor.
我想向博士你借一样东西
A seat belt buckle.
安全带的锁扣
Chiba, come here for a moment.
千叶 过来一下
Yes.
是
Did you find something?
发现什么了吗
Look at this.
你看一下这个
Is it a seat belt buckle?
是安全带的锁扣吗
Don't you think it looks like something was tied there?
这里有好像被绑上过什么一样的
There is a thread-like burn mark, right?
被烧焦的线状痕迹是吧
Really.
真的呢
It's roughly the width of a kite string.
像是和风筝线差不多粗细的绳子
Kite string?
风筝线吗
What are you doing, Mr. Mouri?
叔叔你这是在干嘛啊
I'm going to the maiden voyage party. It's about to start.
去参加首航宴会 马上就要开始了
Mr. Mouri.
毛利先生
Inspector Megure wants to see you for a bit.
目暮警官想让您过去一下
Inspector?
警官吗
I'll be right there.
我这就过去
I'll come with you.
我也去
You stay here and change your clothes.
你给我留在这里换衣服
I see.
原来如此
There is also something suspicious about Hideto Yashiro's accident.
八代英人的那起事故也找到了疑点啊
According to Inspector Sato's investigation,
据佐藤警官的调查
the kite string mark on the seat belt is suspicious.
安全带上的风筝线痕迹总觉得很可疑
How's that, Mouri?
怎么样 毛利
Can you think of anything?
有没有想到什么啊
Even if you say so...
虽然您这样说
What about the other items left behind?
其他的遗留物品呢
Right.
是
There was a burnt can that looked like a juice can,
有被烧黑的像是果汁的易开罐
and also some little things left behind.
好像还有些小东西的残骸
It is said that they've all been disposed of.
据说已经全部处理掉了
A can and kite string?
易开罐和风筝线吗
If someone used that...
只要使用那个的话
Were you surprised?
吓了一跳吧
You little brat!
你这个小鬼
I was planning to shake a Coca-Cola and make it spurt out.
我本来打算摇摇可乐罐让可乐喷出来吓你们的
But there was no Coca-Cola for sale.
可是没有可乐卖
Coca-Cola? How dare you...
居然还想用可乐
I thought my heart was going to stop.
心脏差点停止了
Speaking of being scared by the can...
说到被罐子吓到的话
Stun grenade.
眩晕弹（Stun Grenade）
Perhaps the culprit used a stun grenade.
犯人是不是使用了眩晕弹呢
That's right.
对了对了
What's that, Shiratori? That stun something...
那…那是什么啊 白鸟 那个眩什么弹
Stun grenade, also known as a flash bomb.
是眩晕弹 别名闪光弹
With a bright flash and an explosion, it stuns the opponent's movement.
用强烈闪光和爆炸声来干扰对方的行动
It's shaped and sized like a can
形状大小像易开罐
and it's also a type of hand grenade.
也是手榴弹的一种
For example, the culprit tied a kite string to the stun grenade which had its pin pulled out already,
比如 在预先拔掉保险的眩晕弹上绑上风筝线
then tied that kite string to the seat belt buckle.
再把风筝线系在安全带的锁扣上
When the victim tried to pull down the seat belt buckle...
在想要系安全带拉下锁扣时
I see.
原来如此
Even if he didn't have a heart attack,
就算没有引起心脏病发作
he couldn't drive after he passed out.
震晕后也无法驾驶了
Thus the car just ra n downhill in one go.
车子就沿着下坡一口气冲了出去
But it's not that easy to get a stun grenade...
但眩晕弹会那么容易就
No. In this era, one can get anything as long as he really wants.
不 现在这个世界只要想要就什么都能弄得到手
And if the purpose was to give the victim a shock,
而且只要给对方造成冲击即可
t here was no need to use a real grenade.
没必要非得用真品
A larger firecracker could work too.
所以用大点的拉炮也可以实施
Inspector.
警官先生
We just got a message.
刚才接到报告
It seems that the body of President Yashiro has been found.
好像发现疑似八代会长的遗体了
Captain.
船长
I have something that I wish to talk to you about.
有件事想找你商量一下
What is it?
什么事
It's about the welcome party at 5:00 p.m.
5点开始的欢迎宴会
I hope you can cancel it.
希望您能终止
If the culprit is planning another round of crimes,
如果犯人还在计划下一轮的犯罪行动
there's a good chance that he'll try to use the confusion during the party.
很可能利用宴会的混乱进行
But this is...
可是这个
Please cooperate with us, captain.
拜托了 船长
No, inspector.
不 警官
Let the party go on as usual.
让宴会照常举行吧
Everything will come to light there.
在那里一切都会真相大白
Could it be that... Mouri...
难 难道说 毛利
Are you going to do it again? The usual thing?
又要来了吗 以往的那个
But he's not asleep.
可是没有睡着啊
Are you sure, Mr. Mouri?
不要紧吧 大叔
Well, let's enjoy ourselves.
好了 让我们来好好享受吧
I'll make up for the half day I spent lying in bed!
把白躺的半天连本带利地讨回来
Sonoko, that's enough...
园子 真受不了你
Say, let's go ask Miss Ran.
我说 去问问小兰姐姐
About the you-know-what.
有没有发现那个吧
Yeah, we should.
说得也是
A gold medal made from sea shells?
用贝壳做的金牌
The string was too short, so we could only make it into a bracelet.
绳子太短 只能做成手链了
So you really didn't notice it.
果然没能发现啊
What a pity.
真失望啊
Sorry. I'll go look at it later.
对不起 稍后我一定去瞧瞧
Anyway, I appreciate your thoughtfulness. I'm really happy.
谢谢你们的一片心意 我好高兴
Hello, everyone. Welcome to the Aphrodite.
各位好 欢迎各位来到阿芙洛狄忒号
I will be your host for tonight's party.
今天晚上的宴会由我来为各位主持
My name is Natsuhi Tsujimoto.
我叫辻本夏帆
Thank you all.
谢谢各位
First of all, I would like to introduce the main crew members on this ship.
首先为大家介绍船上的主要工作成员
First is Mr. Naoya Misaki, the chief purser.
首先是乘务长岬直也先生
Next is the doctor on board, Doctor Hitoshi Mizukubo.
接下来是船医水久保医生
And our chef, Katushiko Siomi, who is in charge of food and beverage.
负责餐饮的汐见胜彦厨师长
Do you know who the culprit is?
知道犯人是谁了吗
And our first-mate, Yousuke Izawa.
大副伊泽洋介
But I haven't found any conclusive evidence yet.
但还没找到决定性的证据
Now then, I've kept you waiting.
最后 让大家久等了
Our captain.
我们的船长
Mr. Wataru Kaidou.
海藤渡先生
Before I give my speech,
在我致词之前
I'd like to introduce to you the wonderful woman who designed this ship.
容我先向大家介绍设计了这艘船的优秀女士
The designer, Miss Minako Akiyoshi.
设计师秋吉美波子小姐
Captain!
船长
Is it true that Chief Takae was murdered?
听说贵江社长被杀害了 是真的吗
Rumor has it that President Yashiro is also missing!
有传言说八代会长也行踪不明了
Well...
这个
You're police officers, right?
你们是警官吧
Did you catch the culprit?
犯人抓住了吗
Is it really okay to hold such a party as if everything is fine?
这样若无其事地举办宴会没问题吗
Calm down, everyone, please calm down!
冷静 各位请冷静一下
What happened, exactly?
到底怎么样了啊
No, it's...
不 这个
Mr. Mouri!
毛利先生
Everyone, please calm down.
各位 请冷静下来
There is no need to worry.
各位不用担心
That gruesome serial murderer...
那个胆大妄为的连环杀人犯
has already been identified by me, Kogoro Mouri!
已经被我毛利小五郎锁定了
We've been waiting for you, great detective!
等了你好久了 名侦探
The murderer who killed Chief Takae Yashiro and President Entarou...
先后杀害了八代贵江社长和延太郎会长的犯人
is...
那个人就是
Miss Minako Akiyoshi!
秋吉美波子小姐
It's you!
就是你
This was her revenge for Hideto Yashiro's accident which occurred half a year ago.
杀人动机是为半年前死于交通事故的八代英人报仇
That accident was actually a murder orchestrated by Entarou and his daughter.
那次事故事实上是由延太郎父女一手造成的杀人事件
But... but why would Miss Akiyoshi want to avenge Mr. Yashiro's death?
但…但是 为什么秋吉小姐要为八代先生报仇呢
It's probably because Miss Minako and Mr. Hideto were lovers.
这大概是因为美波子小姐与英人先生曾经是恋人吧
Hold on, Mr. Mouri.
请等一下 毛利先生
I did respect Mr. Yashiro as a great senior.
我的确把八代老师当作伟大的前辈来尊敬
But I didn't have any affair with...
但是说什么恋情…
And I have an alibi.
而且我有
I was on the phone with Mr. Kusaka in my room during the murder.
案发时在房间里和日下先生通电话的不在场证明啊
That's true.
的确
But in fact, you let Mr. Kusaka read his story for about 20 minutes.
但事实上中间约有20分钟的时间你只是让日下先生念故事
In the meantime, you didn't say anything.
自己却一言未发
That means...
也就是说
you don't have an alibi for that period of time.
这段时间内你没有不在场证明
That's enough!
请你适可而止
If Mr. Kusaka had stopped in the middle and asked me something,
如果日下先生念到一半停下来问我什么的话
he'd know I was not on the other end of the phone, right?
不就马上知道我不在电话旁了吗
I'm not as stupid enough to create an alibi like that!
我还没蠢到会用这样的不在场证明
Even so, if you insist on saying that I'm the culprit,
即使如此 你仍说我是犯人的话
please show me the proof.
请马上拿出证据来
You have that, right, Mr. Mouri? The proof...
应该有吧 毛利老弟 证据
Well...
这个
Could it be that...
爸爸他该不会是
he suspected Miss Minako just because she looks like my Mom?
因为美波子小姐长得像妈妈才怀疑她的吧
What's the matter, Mr. Mouri?
怎么样 毛利先生
No, sorry.
不 不好意思
I need a little bathroom break...
现在中场休息（toilet time）
Break?
休…休息
Found it.
找到了
Inspector!
警官
Should we do something while everyone is still laughing?
趁大家都在笑的时候快想想办法吧
But...
但是
Don't worry, Inspector Megure.
不用担心 目暮警官
I already know who the real culprit is.
我已经知道真正的犯人是谁了
Is it true, Professor Agasa?
是真的吗 阿笠博士
Great!
太棒了
This time it's the professor's deduction show!
这次是博士的推理秀呢
Do you know the original meaning of the word "cruise"?
各位知道坐游轮观光（cruise）这个词的本意是什么吗
It refers to an act of piracy
是指一种海盗行为
That is, to keep searching for a prey on the voyage. That is the origin of that word.
为了获取猎物而驾船不停地航行掠夺 这个词就是这样来的
There is a pirate on this ship as well.
然后 在这艘船上也有海盗
This pirate doesn't plunder others' wealth.
他并不是要掠夺他人的财产
Instead, this pirate is actually a murderer who plunders others' lives.
而是掠夺他人性命的名为杀人者的海盗
That's right
没错
This pirate is
这个海盗就是
the script writer, Mr. Hironari Kusaka.
身为编剧的日下宽成先生
It's you.
就是你
You're talking nonsense.
别说些莫名其妙的话啊
Didn't you hear what Miss Minako said?
没有听到美波子小姐的那席话吗
I was reading her my script draft over the phone during the time of the murder.
事件发生时我通过电话在念企划书上的故事给她听啊
Is this the story you were reading?
你所谓的故事是这个吗
Nanami Okazaki loves the sea.
冈崎奈奈美非常热爱大海
Maybe it's because she was born and raised by the sea.
或许是因为在海边土生土长的缘故
She loves its vastness more than anything else.
她喜欢大海的宽广胜于其他任何东西
What a simple trick.
真是很简单的手法啊
You recorded your story in advance, and played it by the phone.
你事先录好故事再对着话筒播放
With that, you went out to commit the crime during that time.
再利用这段时间出去杀人
Impossible! I should have deleted all that!
怎么可能 那个我应该已经全都删掉了
Deleted?
删了
No, you thought it was deleted, but it wasn't.
不 你以为删除了 但是实际上却没有被删掉
Such an important thing like this could kill you, if you don't make sure it was deleted.
这么重要的东西不好好确认一下可是致命的哦
You fabricated the evidence, didn't you?
你捏造了证据是吧
That tape.
那段录音
You used his voice to record it, right?
是你用他的声音录进去的吧
Right.
没错
But there's another conclusive evidence.
但是还有个决定性的证据在
Inspector, that's not enough to prove that I'm the murderer, isn't it?
警官 就凭这个不能成为我杀人的证据吧
Of course we have the evidence.
证据不是有吗
Look, it's right there.
看 就在那里
What's wrong with you?
大哥哥你怎么了啊
There's a blackish part mixed with your red ones.
红色的头发中夹有黑色的哦
Isn't that... blood?
那该不会是血吧
Blood?
血
Please show us, Mr. Kusaka.
请让我们看一下 日下先生
Oh right.
对了
After you did those bad things, you checked how you looked in the mirror.
大哥哥做了坏事后虽然照过镜子
But the color of your hair is very similar to blood, so you didn't notice it.
但头发的颜色和血很相近所以并没有发觉
You should remember this.
不过还是请你记住这点
Blood will clot as time goes on,
血液经过一段时间后会凝固
and it's color will change.
颜色也会发生变化
Could you please take off the scarf around your neck?
顺便请你把围在脖子上的围巾拿下来吧
If my deduction is correct,
如果我的推理正确的话
there should be some bruises there.
那里应该还留有瘀青
They're nail or finger marks left by President Yashiro
那是遭到你袭击后拼命反抗的
when he desperately fought back against your attack.
八代会长留下的指甲印或手指印
Sorry to offend you.
对不起 冒犯了
Mr. Kusaka.
日下先生
May we hear your story in detail in another room?
我们到其他房间去请你详细说明一下吧
Hold on. Stop it.
等一下 讨厌啦
I still have this.
我还有这个
A trump card up my sleeve!
最后一张王牌呢
Nobody move!
不许动
Or I'll detonate the bombs!
动的话我就引爆炸弹
Bombs?
炸弹
If you don't want the ship to sink, then listen carefully to what I'm going say!
不想让船沉没的话就老老实实听我的话
It's him!
就是他
He is the guy who attacked me!
袭击我的就是这个人
You finally remembered?
你总算想起来了啊
Anyway, please calm down for now.
总之请先冷静下来
Why are you doing this?
你为什么要做这种事
I'm taking revenge for my father!
这是为父报仇
Revenge?
报仇
15 years ago,
15年前
the crew member who died in the accident of Yashiro Shipbuilding Company cargo ship
在八代造船公司货轮事故中死去的船员
was my father!
就是我的父亲
So that's it... That was...
原来是这样 那个是…
Two years ago,
两年前
I heard it from one of my father's former colleagues who came to visit his grave...
我从来给父亲扫墓的父亲以前的同事那里听说了
A strange rumor about the accident.
关于那起事故的奇怪的传闻
At that time,
当时
the Chief of Yashiro Shipbuilding Company, Entarou, and Executive Takae
八代造船公司社长延太郎和专职董事贵江
planned to sink the cargo ship for its insurance
以保险金为目的 计划了让货轮沉没的阴谋
and get rid of Captain Okita, who had been working for the welfare of the crew.
并为了除去平时致力于提高船员待遇的冲田船长
They even roped in the first-officer, Kaidou.
还拉拢了副船长海藤
You got talked into it
听从了他们的安排
and put sleeping pills in the captain's coffee to make him fall asleep.
你就让船长喝下有安眠药的咖啡 使他睡着
After that, you crashed the ship to an iceberg on purpose.
然后故意让船撞上冰山
At the same time, you detonated the bombs you'd set up beforehand.
同时引爆了事先装好的炸弹
The locations to put the bombs...
安装炸药的地方
were most likely suggestions from the designer, Hideto Yashiro, right?
恐怕是设计师八代英人指示的吧
How could Mr. Yashiro...
老师他竟然
How did you kill President Yashiro?
你是怎么杀害八代会长的
He got on top of me and choked me with his hands.
那家伙骑在我身上掐住了我的脖子
So I used a Judo throwing technique to throw him into the sea.
我就用柔道里的巴投技把他扔进了大海
And then, just like you did before, I was planning to blow up the ship,
然后打算像你以前所做的那样引爆这艘船
and kill you in the confusion.
趁着混乱杀掉你
What a ridiculous delusion.
可笑的妄想
Hold on. Anyway, please remove your finger from the remote button.
等一下 总之先把手指从遥控器上拿开
Shut up! Don't come any closer!
吵死了 别接近我
He's gone!
他不见了
I won't let you run away!
休想逃
Conan!
柯南
Get him!
快追
Damn it!
可恶
Wait, Conan!
等等 柯南
Wait for us!
请等一下
You guys...
你们
We'll go with you.
我们也去
We can't let you be the hero all by yourself.
不能只让柯南你一个人出风头
Haibara...
灰原
Just like they said.
就这么回事
Hold tight.
别被甩出去哦
Shift to the left!
靠左坐
Now to the right!
这次靠右
We passed him!
超过了
Haibara, take the wheel!
灰原 你来开船
Conan!
柯南
You made it, Conan?
搞定了吗 柯南
Great!
太棒了
The Detective Boys did it again!
少年侦探团 大胜利
Hey, you guys!
喂 你们几个
Hey, are you okay?
喂 没事吧
How can you guys do this?
怎么可以这样呢 你们
He's a murder suspect!
对方可是杀人嫌犯啊
What if something happened to you?
要是有个万一怎么办
Sorry for that.
对不起
Inspector Megure!
目暮警官
How many bombs did he set up?
他到底装了多少炸弹啊
Izawa, how is the situation?
伊泽 情况怎么样
Captain.
船长
The explosion caused several holes to appear in the ship's hull.
因为爆炸船腹出现了好几个洞
How about the watertight doors?
水密门呢
They're closed.
关上了
The water is going from Zone 3 to Zone 4.
海水已经开始从第3区进入第4区了
What?
什么
Captain, please give the order to abandon ship.
船长 请你发出弃船命令
There is black smoke ahead, over.
前方 确认出现黑烟
Captain!
船长
All personnel abandon ship.
全体人员弃船
All passengers!
各位乘客
This is first-officer, Izawa.
我是大副伊泽
Please put on your life jackets and move to the deck on the first floor.
请大家穿好救生衣到1层的甲板
This is not a drill.
这不是演习
I repeat.
再重复一遍
All crew members, please guide the passengers.
全体船员请引导乘客
It's not here.
这里没有啊
The gold medal those kids were talking about? Where did it go?
孩子们说的金牌 到底到哪里去了
Ran!
兰
We're going. Hurry up.
走了 快点
Ran, let's go.
兰 我们走吧
Please don't panic.
请不要慌张
There's still plenty of time.
时间还很宽裕
Please continue moving without pushing.
请不要互相推搡 迅速前进
Dad, where's Conan and the others?
爸爸 柯南他们呢
No need to worry about them.
他们不要紧
Inspector Megure said they went chasing after Kusaka in a motor boat,
目暮警官说他们乘上快艇去追日下
and they were picked up by a nearby yacht.
被救到附近的游艇上了
That's good.
太好了
Ran, you two leave in this boat.
兰 你们乘这艘船走吧
I'll take the other one.
我乘其他的船走
But...
但是
Then, see you later.
那么过会儿见
Dad!
爸爸
Don't rush. Please follow the person in front of you.
不要慌张 请紧跟着前面的人
Once you hit the water, get away from the ship as soon as possible.
一下到海里就要尽快远离这船
If you get sucked down by the ship's whirlpool, no one can save you.
要是被卷入沉船的漩涡 可就没救了
Got it.
知道了
Honey, it's hot and stuffy here.
老公你有没有觉得很闷热啊
Suck it up. This is an emergency.
这种时候你就忍忍吧
But it's really hot. I just can't put up with it.
话虽这么说 可是热得受不了嘛
I remember now.
我想起来了
What?
什么
I dropped it where I hid for the game.
掉在玩捉迷藏的地方了
That gold medal?
那个金牌吗
I'm lowering the raft. Hold on tight.
现在我要把船放下海了 请抓紧
I'm getting off.
我要下去
Ran!
兰
I'll go get it. Just go ahead.
我去拿 你们先走吧
But...
可是
It's just a medal made from shells,
虽然是用贝壳做的金牌
but to me, it's a very precious treasure.
但对我来说是很珍贵的宝物啊
I'll see you later.
那等下再见
Wait, Ran!
等一下 兰
Found it! This is it!
找到了 就是这个
We're really lucky.
我们真是幸运啊
There happened to be a ship nearby.
附近正好有这艘船
Are the people left on that ship all right?
留在船上的人不要紧吧
That's worrying.
真是担心
Relax, she must be in a lifeboat.
放心吧 她一定在救生艇上
Kusaka said he was planning to kill Mr. Kaidou in the confusion,
日下虽然说过他本来是想趁混乱杀死海藤先生的
but even so, aren't there a bit too many bombs?
但就算这样炸弹也太多了点
It's like he was really trying to sink this ship.
这简直就是想让船真的沉没
And come to think of it, isn't that trick he used for his alibi too simple?
而且那个不在场证明 现在想起来也太过单纯了
If Miss Minako had talked to him in the middle,
要是电话打到一半美波子小姐和他说话的话
that trick would fall apart right there, wouldn't it?
不是马上就被揭穿了吗
He probably tested it several times.
大概他试过好几次了吧
Maybe after he confirmed the fact that she would never interrupt,
确认了在自己说话的时候她绝不会插嘴后
then he thought he could use it to create an alibi.
才认为可以利用这个来做不在场证明
It's true that she said it.
确实她也说过
If I interrupted, he'd get angry.
要是中途插嘴他会生气的
Inspector Megure.
目暮警官
I just heard the report from the Coast Guard.
刚刚听了海上保安厅的报告
They found a fruit knife stabbed into President Yashiro's back.
被发现的八代会长背上插着一把水果刀
What?
什么
What does that mean?
到底怎么回事
Kusaka didn't mention anything about a fruit knife.
日下可没提到过水果刀啊
It was at 10:11 a.m
是10点11分
About 10:15 a.m.
10点15分左右
No, it wasn't Kusaka.
不对 不是日下
Then who on earth was it?
那到底是谁
She really doesn't look like she's in her 50s!
一点都不像50多岁啊
Conan!
柯南
Where are you going, Conan?
你要到哪里去啊 柯南
Why is it?
到底怎么了呢
Something just doesn't feel right.
总觉得有点不对劲
I feel like if I just let this continue,
总觉得如果这样发展下去
I'd lose something that I'll never get back. I just have that feeling.
就没有挽回的余地了 我有这种感觉
Are you referring to the case?
难道你指的是事件吗
Maybe.
大概
Perhaps.
也许吧
Conan.
柯南
The case?
事件
Are you sure this is the only reason?
真的只为了这个吗
Kudo.
工藤
If my deduction is correct,
如果我的推理没错
then the real culprit is...
真正的犯人是
Captain.
船长
The evacuation of the passengers is now complete.
乘客的疏散已经完毕
I'll take the life raft.
我坐救生筏
You just go find the other crew members and leave with them first.
你和船员们汇合后先走吧
Understood.
明白了
Huh? Won't you sink with this ship?
咦 你不和这条船共存亡吗
Captain?
船长先生
What are you doing here?
你在这里做什么
Hurry and get out of this ship!
赶快离开这船
Do you still remember this?
还记得这个吗
My father's favorite thing when he was alive.
这是我父亲生前最喜欢的东西
Origami boat?
折纸船
Are you...
莫非
Right.
对
I am the daughter
我就是15年前
of Captain Okita, whom you and the Yashiro family conspired to murder 15 years ago.
你和八代父女合谋杀害的冲田船长的女儿
I'm so sorry.
真不好意思
I've destroyed the remaining life rafts.
剩下的救生筏我已经全毁掉了
How come...
怎么会这样
Don't move!
不许动
It's a bit cramped here.
这里好像狭窄了一点
Let's go somewhere spacious and have a long chat about this while enjoying the salty breeze.
我们到宽敞的地方边吹海风边慢慢谈吧
It was half a year ago.
那是半年前的事了
Kusaka came to interview me for his drama series.
日下说因为电视剧的关系要来采访我
But he was a bit too eager to know about Yashiro and his daughter, who had nothing to do with the interview.
但是他急欲知道和采访完全无关的八代父女的事情
He was even sweating.
而且神色慌张
So, when he left to go to the bathroom...
于是我就趁他去厕所的时候
I saw the truth behind the sinking of the Yashiro Number 1.
看到了第一八代丸沉没事故的真相
That was Kusaka's real purpose.
这才是日下真正的目的
Although I didn't believe it was true,
虽然觉得不可能
I went to ask Hideto Yashiro the following day.
第2天我还是去问了八代英人
After drinking a bit of liquor, he spilled everything.
灌了他一点烈酒他就不停地说了起来
The sinking of that ship was not an accident,
那次沉船的真相不是事故
but an orchestrated event.
而是一起精心策划的事件
He didn't know that I was Captain Okita's daughter.
他却不知道我就是冲田船长的女儿
I'm sorry.
对不起
I was ordered by the Chief.
那是因为社长的命令
Don't make excuses!
不要找借口了
I'll let you go to hell with Yashiro and his daughter.
我就让你跟随八代父女而去吧
Just like my father who died in vain.
就像我冤死的父亲一样
Damn it! Let me get there in time!
可恶 给我赶上啊
Please, let me go...
求求你 放过我吧
Goodbye, captain.
再见了 船长先生
Stop it!
住手
So, as suspected, you're the real culprit.
果然你才是真正的犯人啊
Miss Minako Akiyoshi.
秋吉美波子小姐
Mr. Mouri...
大叔
Don't move!
不许动
Sorry, but that gun doesn't work anymore.
不好意思 那把枪已经不能用了
I found it in your room during my bathroom break.
我利用那次中场休息在你房间里发现的
Captain.
船长
I'll have a long chat with you later.
之后我要和你好好谈谈
Miss Akiyoshi.
秋吉小姐
Based on my deduction...
在我的推理中
Let's stop it.
不要说了
All three of us are going to die anyway.
反正我们3个都要死了
Talking about your deduction on a sinking ship...
在快沉的船上说你的推理
is pointless.
没有任何意义
How can I stop?
我怎么能不说呢
Revealing the truth is what a detective lives for.
揭开真相是侦探的本性
I'm afraid you already knew about Kusaka's plan
恐怕你早就知道了日下策划的
to kill the four of them, including Hideto.
包括英人在内的连续4人的杀人计划
But there was a part of his plan which was impossible to achieve.
但在这计划中有无法实现的部分
So you killed Hideto before Kusaka could do it,
于是你就在日下动手之前先杀害了英人
and made it look like he died of a heart attack.
并伪装成他是心脏病突发而死的
You used a self-made stun grenade.
用了自制的眩晕弹
After Hideto died,
英人死后
Kusaka changed the four murders to just three,
日下的杀人计划从4人减至3人
and decided to use you to create an alibi.
并决定利用你作不在场证明
Knowing that, you decided to use his plan to take revenge with your own hands.
你知道后反而决定利用他的计划亲自复仇
First, you set up bombs separately from Kusaka's bombs.
你首先和日下在不同地方安置了炸弹
This is a ship you designed.
这可是自己设计的船
You know best which parts would make this ship sink if they were blown up.
在哪里安装炸弹会对船造成致命伤你最清楚
Then, at 10:00 a.m. this morning,
然后早上10点
you answered a phone call from Kusaka.
你接听了日下的电话
Just as he started reading the story, you dashed out of your room.
他一开始读故事你就马上跑出房间
You knocked out Chief Takae who was taking a bath,
把正在洗澡的贵江社长弄昏过去
put on the bathrobe and pretended to be Chief Takae.
披上浴巾装成贵江社长
After that, Kusaka sneaked in.
之后偷偷溜进来的日下
He thought you, wearing a bathrobe, were Chief Takae.
认定了披着浴巾站着的你就是贵江社长
You pretended to try to grab his knife,
你装成要抢他刀的样子
and deliberately stabbed it into your stomach where you'd put a fake blood bag.
故意刺入自己腹部事先准备好的道具血袋
After Kusaka left, thinking he had done what he came for,
在自认为目的已达成的日下逃走后
you killed Chief Takae.
你就杀害了贵江社长
Then you wiped away the fake blood that dripped onto the floor,
随后你把滴落到地上的假血擦干净
put on the windbreaker and walked out of the room.
穿上风衣走出房间
At that time, I thought it was because you didn't want your face to be seen that you turned your back to me.
那时候我以为是为了不想让自己的脸被看到才背向我
But then I realized,
但之后我察觉到
that person might be a woman.
那个人说不定是女人
She did it because she was consciously trying to protect her chest.
下意识要保护胸部才这样做
I see.
原来如此
That's why at that time...
所以那个时候
Afterwards, you went straight to the basement marina.
随后你直接走到地下船坞
When you got there, it was when the president
那时会长就正好
was sitting on top of Kusaka and choking him.
骑在日下身上掐他的脖子
You quickly ran to the two of them,
你迅速地跑到他们两人身边
grabbed both feet of the president.
抓住了会长的双脚
Both feet?
双脚
That's right.
没错
You went behind him without touching his feet,
你避开他的双脚到他的背后
and stabbed him in the back.
用刀刺进了他的背
Right, right...
对 对
Then, you left the scene as soon as possibly,
然后 你迅速离开现场
letting Kusaka believe he did it.
让日下以为是自己干的
Everything has happened just as you planned.
一切正如你所愿
As expected of the famous detective, Kogoro Mouri.
不愧是名侦探毛利小五郎啊
The reason why I used that man
我之所以会想利用那个男的
is because I knew you'd be on this ship too.
是因为知道你也会上这艘船
In order to fool the eyes of the famous detective,
为了瞒过名侦探的眼睛
it was necessary to design a fake culprit.
是有必要设计一个假犯人的
Moreover, this culprit must believe that he was the culprit.
而且 这个犯人还得真以为是自己干的
One more thing.
还有一点
In the article on his laptop,
他在电脑的文章里
he called my father, who went down with the ship, the representation of an anachronism.
谴责我父亲与那艘船共存亡的行为不符合时代精神
I will never forgive anyone who insults my father.
任何侮辱父亲的人我都不能原谅
You are the one who can't be forgiven.
不能原谅的人是你啊
Not only did you take the lives of those three,
你不单夺走了3条人命
you put a lot of innocent people in danger as well.
还令其他那么多无辜的人身陷危险
In the end, you even sank the ship you designed yourself.
最后甚至让自己设计的船沉没
I've done many detailed simulations.
我可是做过很多次精密的模拟实验的
The number of bombs,
炸弹的数量
the amount of seawater entering the ship,
进水时涌入的海水量
the time it takes for the evacuation...
避难所需要的时间
then I would get what I wanted,
然后就可以得到一个结果
the scene where that sneaky man standing over there
就是那个站在那里鬼鬼祟祟的男人
die in this boundless ocean,
在这汪洋大海上
just like my father,
像父亲一样
swallowed by loneliness and despair.
陷入被孤独和绝望所包围的情景
Besides,
而且
Aphrodite is a goddess born from foam,
阿芙洛狄忒是在泡沫中诞生的女神
it is her destiny to return to nothing.
命中注定她会回归泡沫
But since you've already figured out this much, I guess I have no choice
不过你已经知道了这么多我也没有办法了
but simply turn myself in.
只好干脆地自首了
I have my principles. I don't fight with women.
我原则上从不和女人动手的
Isn't that sexist?
你这不是性别歧视吗
Mr. Mouri...
大叔
How's that? Are you still sticking to your principles?
如何 这样还不能改变你的原则吗
It's not my principle to fight meaninglessly either.
打无意义的架也不是我的原则
Didn't you say that all three of us would die here anyway?
你不是说反正我们3个都会死在这里吗
That's because you're getting in the way of my revenge!
那是因为你妨碍了我的复仇计划
That boy...
那孩子
Shinichi?
新一
No, no, no...
不是 不是
Should we finish this?
我们还是快点结束吧
Mr. Kogoro Mouri.
毛利小五郎先生
I hate to see a famous detective in such a mess, but...
我还真不想看到 名侦探的这副狼狈样呢
Mind your own business.
不劳你费心
Mr. Mouri...
叔叔
How unlucky
我真不走运啊
that I had the famous detective suspect me from the very start.
从一开始就引起了名侦探的注意
I guess I'm a lot like some woman you hate?
看来我和某个你很讨厌的女人很像吧
Just the opposite.
正好相反啊
Because you look like her,
正因为你和她很像
I thought, as long as the culprit wasn't you, it would be fine.
我想犯人不是你就好了
So I was trying to collect evidence to prove your innocence.
就去收集能证明你无罪的证据
But it turned out like this.....
才变成这样的
Mr. Mouri...
叔叔
Are you okay, Mr. Mouri?
不要紧吧 叔叔
That was a good deduction, Mr. Mouri.
真是名推理啊 大叔
What are you doing here?
你怎么会到这里来
Forget about that for now. We gotta go!
别管这个了 叔叔 得赶快逃啊
Go?
逃
We can't.
不行了
The lifeboats have all left.
救生艇已经全开走了
The life rafts have all been destroyed by this woman.
救生筏都被这个女人毁了
Captain!
船长
We're saved...
有救了
Why is it? This feeling...
怎么了 这种感觉
The case has already been solved.
案子明明已经解决了啊
Why do I feel restless and unsettled?
我怎么觉得心情这么沉重 心中忐忑不安的
The ship is going to sink soon.
船马上要沉了
Please hurry up.
请快点
It's your turn. Hurry!
轮到你了 快点
What are you doing? Get on!
你在干什么呀 快上去啊
Where's Miss Ran?
小兰姐姐呢
Ran has already gotten on a lifeboat, hasn't she?
兰不是已经上了救生艇吗
Mr. Mouri, aren't you with Ran?
叔叔 您没有和小兰在一起吗
What happened?
发生什么事了
She said she was going back to her hiding spot to get her gold medal.
她说要去玩捉迷藏的地方拿她的金牌
So, I thought she was with you.
所以 我以为她和你们在一起呀
That's it!
就是这个
Wait a minute!
等一下
Where is Ran, exactly?
兰到底在哪里啊
Anyone?
有人吗
Anyone outside?
有没有人啊
Ran, you're really here!
兰 你果然在这里啊
Shinichi, you'll definitely find me, right?
新一 你一定能找到我吧
Shinichi...
新一
Where is Ran?
兰到底在哪里
Miss Ran said she knew I was kicking the soccer ball here the entire time.
小兰姐姐说过她知道我一直在这里踢球
That means...
也就是说
She's up there!
在这上面
I will find you.
我会找到你的
I will definitely find you.
一定会找到你的
Wait for me, Ran!
等着我 兰
Where is Ran?
兰在哪里啊
Calm down. Calm down and think.
冷静 冷静地想一想
I found her easily at that time, didn't I?
那时候不是很容易就找到了她吗
Come to think of it...
对了
How did you know where I was hiding?
你怎么知道我藏在哪里啊
You were kicking your soccer ball the entire time, weren't you?
你不是一直在专心踢足球吗
Conan, you were kicking the soccer ball the entire time, right?
柯南你一直在踢足球吧
I knew it all along.
我可是知道得一清二楚哦
So that's it. Both that day and today...
原来如此 那时候和今天都…
Mr. Mouri.
叔叔
Are there any places
那附近的地板上
where you can hide around the floor?
有没有可以让人躲起来的地方
I found one!
找到一个
Damn it, it won't open.
可恶 打不开啊
Mr. Mouri!
叔叔
It worked.
开了
Ran!
兰
Are you there, Ran?
你在吗 兰
Dad...
爸爸
She's down there.
她在啊
We must hurry up, Mr. Mouri, or we can't make it.
不快点就来不及了 叔叔
Damn it!
可恶
Not good. Not good...
不好了 不好了
If we don't turn around the lifeboat soon, Ran and the others will die!
不快点把救生艇开回去的话兰他们就会没命的
Sorry, but I can't do that.
很抱歉 这个办不到
If we get closer now,
现在靠近的话
I'm afraid we'll get caught in the sinking ship's whirlpool.
我们恐怕会被沉船的漩涡卷进去
How can that be?
怎么会
The Coast Guard's rescue chopper!
海上保安厅的救援直升机
Great!
太好了
It's a rescue chopper!
是救援直升机
Damn it...
糟了
Let's go to the bow.
逃到船头去吧
Over here!
在这里
Are you the only ones on the ship?
船上就你们几个人了吗
Yes.
是的
Boy, just hold on a little longer.
小朋友 再忍耐一下就好
W e're going to save you right now.
我们现在就救你们了
Listen, hold on to me.
听好啊 紧紧地抓住我
Now they're going to pull us up.
现在要把我们拉上去了
Please hold on to your daughter firmly.
请您好好支撑住您的女儿
Okay.
好的
Are you okay?
你怎么样
Grab my hand!
抓住我
Damn it!
可恶
Hold on tight, Conan...
抓紧我 柯南
Are you all right?
不要紧吧
Boy.
小朋友
Give me your hand.
把手给我吧
We'll arrive soon.
马上就到了
Thank you.
谢谢
The boat which your parents are in is closeby.
你们妈妈的船也到附近了哦
So...
那么说
The reason you thought she was the culprit
你之所以会认定是她作的案
is because Kusaka's alibi was too simple?
是因为日下的不在场证明过于单纯了啊
The reason such a simple alibi worked
能让这么单纯的不在场证明成立
is because the one on the other end, Miss Minako.
是因为对方的美波子小姐
She wanted to use this alibi as well.
也有将其加以利用的企图才能成功
Besides, the only one who could disguise herself as Chief Takae, who had such a pair of beautiful legs,
而且 能假扮拥有美腿的贵江社长的人
is Miss Minako with the same beautiful legs, right?
就只有同样拥有美腿的她了吧
I see.
原来如此啊
But how did you know where Ran was?
不过你怎么知道小兰的所在呢
That's because...
那是因为
I was more worried about you...
我才为你担心呢
I was actually kicking a volleyball,
那时我其实是在踢排球
but Miss Ran said I was kicking a soccer ball.
小兰姐姐却说我是在踢足球
So I guessed she was hiding somewhere where she could only hear the sound.
所以我猜她是藏在一个能听到声音的地方吧
But it's really disappointing.
不过真遗憾
I'm glad that Ran was saved,
虽然兰得救了我很高兴
but I thought the only one who could find and save Ran was Kudo...
但我还以为只有工藤才能找到并救出兰呢
No, the reason she was saved is because...
不 会得救是因为…
Miss Ran!
小兰姐姐
We fixed the gold medal!
我们修好金牌了哦
This time we used a longer string so that you can put it on your neck.
这次为了使你能戴在脖子上特地把绳子加长了
I'll put it on for you.
我来帮你戴吧
Thank you.
谢谢
It looks good on you.
跟你挺相称嘛
I'll cherish it.
我会好好珍惜它的
T he reason she was saved is because
会得救是因为
there were those guys'
有他们凝聚其中的
who were empathetic.
那体谅彼此的心意啊